# **Jack Kershaw**

hello@jackkershaw.net jackkershaw.net 07787 075097 linkedin.com/in/jackkershaw github.com/jackkershaw/

I am a graduate and frontend developer with a strong passion for creating beautiful and functional products that enhance user experience. My proactive and organised approach to work drives me to build new projects and learn new technologies.

# **Skills**

### **Frameworks:**

Next.js, React, Astro, FastHTML

#### Frontend:

Typescript, JavaScript, Tailwind, SASS, Styled Components

### **Backend:**

Python and MySQL, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Postman

### **DevOps:**

Git, Github, CI/CD with Vercel and Netlify

### **Further Technical Skills:**

Docker, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, Final Cut Pro, Squarespace, Wordpress, BigCartel

# **Education**

#### **Web Development Course**

Just IT, October 2023 - January 2024

### **BA Greek with Latin**

University College London, 2016-2020

## **A-Levels**

Latin A, Ancient Greek A, Maths B **GCSEs** 

## 6 A\*, 3A

# **Experience**

See my Portfolio and GitHub for further examples of my work.

## **Frontend Developer**

### Octopus Energy, July 2024 - Present

- Won the Tech Zero x Kraken Hackathon in July 2024, resulting in a £20,000 prize and mentorship from Octopus Energy.
- Currently building an open-source product in Next.js which encourages neighbours to share and expand solar capacity, with a community map and data sourced from the Google Solar API.

## **Full Stack Developer**

### Fare Free London, June 2024 - August 2024

- Delivered a fast, secure, and easily updatable website for a public transport campaign by using Next.js and Headless WordPress.
- Debugged security issues by moving Airtable signup form requests server-side and responded to user feedback via GitHub Issues.

## **Frontend Developer**

## Take Back Water, February 2024 - June 2024

- Employed as a contractor within a team of developers.
- Enhanced website accessibility and performance, achieving a perfect score of 100 across all Lighthouse categories.
- Upgraded the SEO of the site using meta tags, ensuring it now performs well in search engines.
- Improved my Git workflow and team-working skills by developing new React components using Figma, Storybook and SASS.

## **Frontend Developer**

### **London Brutalist Map**, January 2024 - September 2024

- Improved developer and user experience by rebuilding my previous HTML project in a multi-page site with React Router for navigation, offering various ways to engage with the data.
- Used Tailwind CSS to create a consistent and accessible design.
- Responded to user feedback by adding a custom marker to handle hover events and enhance interactivity.

# **Director and Graphic Designer**

### **Tapir Studio Limited**, September 2019 - December 2023

- Designed posters, websites, and social media branding for clients such as Oxford University and Common Knowledge, and managed company digital infrastructure to ensure smooth dayto-day operations.
- Led the brand design for La Fête de L'Humanité in 2022 and 2023, significantly contributing to the event's success in attracting over 500,000 attendees.
- Achieved international recognition with features in major media outlets, including a double-page spread in the Guardian and articles in Vice and It's Nice That.